Collection of Materials about Joseph Scott LSC.0776
UCLA Library Special Collections
Collection of Materials about Joseph Scott
1910-1950
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0776
2.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
7 audiovisual carriers (7 records)
Joseph Scott (1867-1958) practiced law in Los Angeles, California, was the president of the school board (1906-11), director (1907-18) and president of the board of the Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce (1910), a member of the Charter Revision Committee (1902), president of the Los Angeles Community Chest (1931-35) and of the California Conference of Social Work (1935-36), and dean and dean emeritus of Loyola of Los Angeles School of Law. The collection consists of Scott's correspondence, photographs, pamphlets, newspaper and magazine ephemera, banquet programs, and audio recordings.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO MATERIALS: Audio materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Acquired by Doyce B. Nunis, July 1960.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942328113606533
Biography/History
Scott was born on July 16, 1867 in Penrith, England. He attended Ushaw College in Durham and University of London, after which he came to the U.S. in 1889. He earned his AM (1893) and LL.D, from the St. Bonaventure College, Allegheny, New York (1914). In 1894 he was admitted to the bar and began practice in Los Angeles, California thereafter. Scott was president of the school board from 1906 to 1911. Scott was also an active member of the board of the Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce, serving as its director from 1907 until 1918 and as its president in 1910. In 1902 Scott was a noted member of the Charter Revision Committee. He was president of the Los Angeles Community Chest from 1931 until 1935 and of the California Conference of Social Work from 1935 to 1936. Scott was also dean and dean emeritus of Loyola of Los Angeles School of Law; and he was appointed Privy Chamberlain of the Sword and Cape by Pope Pius XII. Scott died on March 24, 1958.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, pictures, pamphlets, newspaper and magazine ephemera, banquet programs relating to the career and organizational leadership of Joseph Scott. Also included are seven master records of the America First Committee and Senator B.K. Wheeler. Correspondence contains letters to Scott from Herbert Hoover, Earl Warren, and William G. McAdoo, and telegrams to Scott from Cardinal Pacelli and Montini Sostituto.
Organization and Arrangement
Items in this collection have been arranged according the document type. The correspondence in the collection is grouped together according to individual correspondents.
Lawyers -- California -- Los Angeles; Civic leaders -- California -- Los Angeles; Civic leaders; Lawyers; California -- Los Angeles; Scott, Joseph, 1867-1958
- Banquet programs, ca. 1915-1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General
  Banquets for William Howard Taft, Knights of Columbus, The Merchants Association, and […in honor of] Archbishop John Cardinal Farley.
- Banquet programs, ca. 1915-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Banquets for William Howard Taft, Knights of Columbus, The Western Fruit Jobbers Association, Capt. Roald Amundsen, Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce welcoming Mr. Andrew Carnegie, and […in remembrance of] James Connolly.
- Correspondence, 1927-1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Letters from President Herbert Hoover, J. Edgar Hoover, Earl Warren and other political and religious dignitaries.
- Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Three telegrams to Joseph Scott from Cardinal Pacelli and Montini Sostituto.
  Scope and Content
  One original version and two photographic facsimiles.
- Publications, 1900-1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Connolly, C.P. "Joe Scott, Orator". The Columbiad. March 1917. New Haven, Conn: Knights of Columbus National Organ.
  Scott, Joseph. "Through the Gates Ajar." 1927. An Address before The Sunset Club Squirrel Inn, Sunday Morning, June 19, 1927. Private Circulation.
  Scott, Joseph and Anderson & Anderson. April 10th, 1900. In the Supreme Court of the State of California: James Cussen (Plaintiff and Respondent) vs. The Southern California Bank, a Corporation Defendant and Appellant - Brief on behalf of the Respondent. Los Angeles: Bowers & Candy, Law Printers.
  Includes a duplicate copy of "Through the Gates Ajar."
- Periodicals, 1900-1927 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Newspaper clipping and two magazines, The Tidings and Town Talk: the pacific weekly
- Photographs, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Pictures of Joseph Scott in attendance with professionals and clergymen and a photograph of Ushaw College.
- Photographs and photographic postcards, 1904-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Pictures and Portraits of Joseph Scott and family, friends, colleagues, and dignitaries. J. Scott on "Bright Angel Trail", Grand Canyon, Arizona, June 26, 1909. "Pricking Coconut Milk at Mazatlan", n.d. Bishop Cartwell, n.d. J. Scott at Camp Elliot, n.d. Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce, San Francisco, CA., 1910. Hillhurst Park, Los Angeles, n.d. The Explosion of the Russian Gunboat Korietz at Chemulpo port, Korea, Febraury 9, 1904. Scott family portrait, Pasadena, CA., 1949. Chaplin trial, n.d. 84th birthday celebration, 1951. 27th Annual Outing September 15, 1940. Uplifter Ranch, Sept. 19, 1931. Dedication to Mount Verne May 16, 1930. Americanism Parade, Beverly Hills, CA., August, 6, 1944. Our Lady of Guadalupe ceremonies, December 14, 1942. Special Naval Ceremonies, San Diego, CA., August 3, 1946. Los Angeles Coliseum, May 4, 1952. Dedication of the new Hall of Justice, Pasadena, CA., n.d.
- Photographs, 1938-1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Pictures of Joseph Scott at various events with other political and religious dignitaries. Boys' Week with Chairman Joseph Scott and the Boy Officials. Third Annual Lincoln Anniversary Banquet of the Lincoln Clubs of Arizona, Phoenix Arizona, February 14. Dinner at Victor Hugo, April 26, 1938. J. Scott with Col. Charles Decker, n.d.
- Photographs, 1926-1938 (Box 2)
  Unframed rolled photographs, including portraits, group pictures and some scenic views. Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce, n.d.. State Convention for the Knights of Columbus, San Francisco, CA., June 1, 1926. 56th International Convention for the Knights of Columbus, August 16-18, 1938. Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce Excursion, Teotihuacan, Mexico, n.d.
- Photographs, 1938-1945 (Box 3)
  Collage of beach of photographs, portraits, group photographs of the Sunset Club. 50th Anniversary Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce, Biltmore Hotel, Los Angeles, CA., October 12, 1938. All-America Football Conference, California Club, Los Angeles, CA., December 4, 1944. Annual Banquet - Friends Sons of St. Patrick of Los Angeles, California Club, Los Angeles CA., March 17, 1941. Sunset Club - Christmas Jinx, December 28, 1945.
  Includes a portrait of Raymond J. Kelly, Commander of the American Foreign Legion, 1939–1940.
- 12" master recordings, 1941; 7 audiovisual carriers (7 records) (Box 4)
  America First Committee, June 20, 1941, Pasadena and Hollywood Bowl, J. Scott and C. A. Lindberg; America First Committee, Hollywood Bowl, June 22, 1941, J. Scott and Senator Clark; and St. Charles, Illinois, September 1, 1941, Senator B.K. Wheeler.